so the critical thing about the eco
village movement is that it represents a
global experiment in sustainability so
these are the people who on these little
projects and communities all over the
world are actually doing what everyone
else advocates but doesn't do in
universities and government agencies and
United Nations it's all doing reports
about sustainability and all the things
we ought to do and how we ought to live
in order to basically you know
ameliorate climate change and create a
sustainable society but who's actually
out on the frontier and the Eco village
movement is a network of communities
that have been doing this for 30 years
taken together then they cut they
basically comprise a global experiment
in sustainability that's been going for
three decades because of that there's
incredible learning incredible wisdom
that has been told now and is now being
brought together and offered to the
world through the guy education program
for example of the global eco village
network which is a training that draws
on the wisdom that has been garnered in
these communities about 80 communities
in 20 countries over the last three
decades so this is a really critical
moment for our civilization as we as we
grope for solutions to some of the most
intractable environmental problems and
the global eco village network is a
network of communities that are coming
up with those solutions in very
practical and integral ways the other
key feature about these communities is
that they address so many features of
our global crisis in one integral
solution for example they address the
ecological issues they address economic
issues they address social issues
providing much more of a community life
and a solution to the alienation that
people tend to experience in urban
industrial cultures they reclaim a
sustainable village life they address
gender issues between women and men all
of these different issues are integrated
so you know traditionally the the major
institutions of our society like the
United Nations for example they have the
Department of the Environment you and
you
and then they have the social summit
they had in Copenhagen then they had the
Women's Conference in Beijing and they
had the the environmental summit in Rio
de Janeiro and in a certain sense what
eco villages do is they integrate all of
these different agendas into practical
integral solutions on the ground now
they're not a utopia there's lots of
failings there's a lot of learning but
they point the way to the future and as
such they are beacons of hope for the
future of humanity